linkedin.com/in/shubhrosinha

SUMMARY

A technology enthusiast with 12+ years of experience in Cloud and Distributed Computing, Scalable systems, L3/L4 Networking, Operating Systems, Memory management, and File systems.

Technical Skills

• Languages: Go, C, Scheme

Technologies: Linux, TCP/IP, Docker, Electron

EXPERIENCE

• Ionos Networks Inc./IPCore Solutions Pvt. Ltd

Bengaluru, KA

Cloud Dataplane Lead/Architect

Nov 2014 - Present

Email: shubhro22@gmail.com

Mobile: +91-9986619004

- Quantum File Transfer(QFX): QFX is a file sync solution that can operate at Gigabit speeds over intercontinental distances. The software is built to scale to 10 million files and 10 terabytes of data. I was responsible for architecture of the dataplane and led a small team of engineers to develop software for
 - * Secure file/directory sync
 - * Dynamic path detection and healing
 - * High speed data transport engine over TCP/IP
 - * End to end congestion control
 - * Network resource allocation and management
 - * Fault tolerance and resiliency
 - * Multicast file transfer
 - * Client apps on MacOS and Linux

• CSR India Pvt. Ltd

Bengaluru, KA

Senior Software Engineer

- o CSR's Synergy Wi-Fi Software Stack A Wi-Fi Soft-Mac solution:
 - $\ast~802.11\mathrm{ac}$ Wi-Fi driver using mac 802.11 Linux stack over PCIe
 - * Requirement analysis, design and development of Wi-Fi features like scanning, 802.11d and 802.11h
 - * Various bug fixes related 802.11 MAC in software Stack
- Sandvine India Pvt. Ltd.

Bengaluru, KA

Sr. Engineer

May 2012 - Dec 2012

- o Sandvine's Signaling Controller A PCRF cum diameter switch:
 - * Modification and Enhancement of Linux Virtual Server (LVS) module to support SNAT and DNAT traffic.
- Brocade Communications India Pvt. Ltd.

Bengaluru, KA

Software Engineer II

• Mindtree Ltd.

Apr 2011 - May 2012

- o Brocade's Project Mercury Brocade's first chassis based Ethernet Switch:
 - * Developed a dynamic Kernel Module Tracing Infrastructure to profile various kernel calls.
 - * Developed a process sandboxing framework to protect system against malicious programs.

Bengaluru, KA

Jul 2007 - Apr 2011

Module Lead/Sr. Engineer/Engineer

• Embedded Software Practice:

- * Design and Development of SIP based 2-way Video Conferencing feature on Android
- * DRTL Implementation of a deadline aware scheduler, Deadline aware locking, and deadline ware interrupt handling in the linux kernel
- * Remotification of WiFi driver companion application and driver enhancements for a series of Wi-Fi chipsets
- * Development of Linux device drivers for Touch screen controllers on Atmel AT91SAM9261/AT91RM9200 platform. (I2C, SPI, GPIO)

Jan 2013 - Nov 2014

EDUCATION

• Birla Institute of Technology and Science

Master of Technology in Software Systems (Work Integrated Learning Program); CGPA: 8.10

Pilani, India

Jul. 2017 - Jul. 2019

• Bengal Engineering and Science University, Shipbur (now IIEST, Shibpur)

Howrah, India Aug. 2003 – July. 2007

Bachelor of Engineering in information Technology; 81.2%

• Holy Mission High School

CBSE - AISSCE(XII); 84%

Samastipur, Bihar

2001

• Central Public School

CBSE - AISSE(X); 85%

Samastipur, Bihar

1999

Publications and Presentations

- "Deployment Specific Real Time Linux" on 23rd Sep, 2009 at the 1st LinuxCon in Portland, OR, USA
- "An Efficient Technique for Enhancing Forensic Capabilities of Ext2 file system" at the 7th Annual Digital Forensic Research Workshop in Pittsburgh, PA, USA.

Achievements/Rewards

- 1. Outstanding performer of the year 2008-09
- 2. Half-yearly award 2008
- 3. Team Spot award Dec 2007
- 4. Topper in campus learning program conducted by MindTree Ltd
- 5. School Topper in AISSCE-2001
- 6. Awarded National Scholarship for getting All India Highest in Science in AISSE 1999